<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Performance Hall Docs</title>
 <link href="performancehall.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="performancehall.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2016-02-05T17:51:25-06:00</updated>
 <id>performancehall.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Kyle McCornack</name>
   <email>kpmccornack@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>Grand Tutorial</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/_posts/2016-01-21-grand-tutorial.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-21T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/_posts/grand-tutorial</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h1 id=&quot;what-the-grand-is&quot;&gt;What the Grand Is&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our Grand Curtain is a manually operated dual curtain system used to cut the
stage (usually very far downstage) in order to create dramatic opening and
finale effects.
It consists of:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Two (2) batton mounted frames, one upstage, one downstage, which support three of the four pulleys,
 and support the track on which the curtain carriers run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Four (4) pulleys, three of which reside on the frame pieces, and one of which lives on the ground during operation of the curtain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Fifty-six (56) single curtain carriers. One single curtain carrier lives at the offstage end of each frame piece, closest to the pulley.
The remaining 54 single carriers are evenly distributed on the tracks of each of the frame pieces, and support and enable the movement of the curtain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grand_pics/grand_10.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Single Carrier&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Two (2) master curtain carriers. One master carrier lives on each track as the furthest on-stage carrier, after all the single carriers have been placed.
The master carriers serve to clamp the rope to segment it into two pieces, which is essential for the proper operation of the curtain. More on this later.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grand_pics/grand_8.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Master Carrier&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Four (4) end stops. Two of these live towards the offstage ends of the carrier track, and two of these live at the onstage ends of the track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grand_pics/grand_9.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;End Stop&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;One (1) rope. The rope forms a loop that connects through all the curtain carriers and pulleys and (ideally, if the curtain is set up correctly)
  permits the opening and closing of the Grand Curtain.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Two (2) curtains.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;how-the-grand-works&quot;&gt;How the Grand Works&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The two most important concepts to comprehend in order to understand the operation of the Grand are:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The free/restricted movement of the curtain carriers on the track&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The movement of the rope through the pulleys and how this influences the movement of the curtain carriers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;on-the-rope&quot;&gt;On the Rope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When set up properly, the rope forms a giant loop that connects through:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The pulley on the floor (from where the curtain is operated)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The downstage stage left vertical pulley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The downstage curtain carriers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The stage right horizontal pulley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The upstage curtain carriers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The upstage vertical pulley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The pulley on the floor to complete the loop.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The rope is divided into two segments via clamping at the two master carriers. One of these segments consists of everything that is &lt;strong&gt;stage left&lt;/strong&gt;
of the downstage master carrier that the rope comes in contact with, so:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The downstage single carriers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The downstage vertical pulley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The ground pulley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The upstage vertical pulley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The rope between the upstage vertical pulley and the upstage master carrier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other segment consists of everything that is effectively &lt;strong&gt;stage right&lt;/strong&gt; of the downstage master carrier:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The rope between the downstage master carrier and the stage right horizontal pulley&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The stage right horizontal pulley itself&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The upstage single curtain carriers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The upstage master curtain carrier&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The segmentation / clamping at the master carriers is one of the integral parts of the movement of the curtain.
If not for this, the rope would just move mostly unimpeded through the single carriers and the curtain would not move along with the rope.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Given this importance, it is pertinent to have the proper lengths of rope in each segment,
and the proper amount of slack distributed between the segments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When initially setting up the rope, you must size the rope lengths to the stage right segment. The stage left segment is slightly more
flexible in terms of the acceptable range of rope length and permittable slack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-movement-of-the-rope&quot;&gt;The Movement of the Rope&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the rope is clamped at the two master carriers, pulling on one of the two vertical segments of rope from the floor position
either closes or opens the curtain. This works because the rope is fixed at the master carriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you imagine a position at upstage center to be 12 o clock, closing the curtain moves the rope and the carriers clockwise around the loop, and opening the curtain moves the
rope/carriers counterclockwise around the loop. The master carriers are hooked to the onstage edges of the curtain. The single carriers are hooked onto the rest of the grommets with the most offstage grommet hooked to a carrier that is secured behind a bracket on the track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the curtain is closed and the master carriers are pulled onstage the master carriers will pull the curtain edges taught and cause the single carriers to pseudo-follow the rope as they follow the grommets on the curtain to which they are connected as the curtain is gradually pulled taught. When the curtain is opened the master carriers will be pulled offstage and will collide with the single carriers, pulling them offstage with it. This will pull the curtain along with the grommets similar to the action when closing the curtain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that you hopefully understand the movement of the curtain, let’s tell you how to actually build it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;building-the-curtain&quot;&gt;Building the Curtain&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First gather the parts and tools you’ll need. These include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The single and master curtain carriers
&lt;br /&gt;   These live in a plastic bin in the stage right upstage wing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The rope - Lives in another plastic bin by the bin for the carriers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Crescent wrenches - Live in Janice on one of the lower-ish shelves&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patience - Find it inside yourself&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fly in U2, assuming the frame for the Grand is still built out on it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;placing-the-curtain-carriers-on-the-track&quot;&gt;Placing the Curtain Carriers on the Track&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first thing you need to do is remove the end stops from the onstage ends of the track.
You’re doing this in order to place the curtain carriers on the track.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the end stops are off, place twenty-seven (27) single carriers on each track.
These need to be placed so that the fold guides are pointing downstage. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the single carriers are all placed, count them again to make sure you have 27 on each side,
then place one master carrier on each track, these should be oriented so that the metal posts on the downstage
master carriers point downstage, and so that the posts on the upstage master carrier point upstage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the carriers are all in place, check again to make sure you have the proper number of carriers on each track,
then replace and resecure the end stops at the onstage ends of the tracks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the end stops are in place you can begin to thread the rope through the pulleys and carriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;threading-the-rope&quot;&gt;Threading the Rope&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Begin by threading the rope through the floor pulley. With the pulley placed on the floor and the knob facing stage left and you,
thread the rope through the gap in the top on the right hand side, staying between the pulley and the bar. Continue feeding the rope along
the wheel, staying inside the posts, until you can bring the rope up out the other side of the gap at the top.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now feed the end of the rope that you pulled through the left side of the gap through the downstage, stage left vertical pulley.
With this pulley, (and with its upstage cousin later on) take the rope up and outside the bottom bar, then feed it along the
wheel and the inside of the posts until you can come out the onstage gap that leads to the curtain carriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re through that pulley, feed it through the big holes of the downstage single carriers, starting with the one closest to the vertical pulley
(this is stage left of the offstage endstop and may be hard to see, as it’s very close to the pulley). Feed the rope through all the big holes on the single carriers one after the other, making sure not to skip any.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve finished threading the downstage single carriers, skip the downstage master carrier for now, and pull the rope to the stage right horizontal pulley.
Thread through the stage right horizontal pulley. Feed the rope through the inner gap, around the wheel, again, staying on the inside of the bar in the back. However,
once you’re around the back and the rope is along the wheel, skip going back through the inner gap and feed the rope through the offstage single carrier’s hole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grand_pics/grand_11.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stage Right Pulley&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now feed through the rest of the upstage single carriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re through all the single carriers, pull the master carrier to the onstage end of the track. Now pull the rope so that you have about a foot and a half of slack at the master carrier at the end of the track. Push the rope into the the gap between the metal posts of the master carrier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Have someone go to the downstage master carrier and pull it as far onstage as it will go. Have the upstage person
hold their end of the rope, and have the downstage person pull the rope towards stage left so the rope is taught. With the rope taught,
or mostly taught, place the rope into the gap between the metal posts on the downstage master carrier, leaving a little slack,  and clamp the rope in place.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you can feed the stage left part of the rope (the end that isn’t the one you’ve been working with this whole time) through the upstage vertical pulley,
like you did before with the other one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’re through the pulley pull that end of the rope to the upstage master carrier. Pull it so that you have about the same amount of slack on that end as on the other end, shove both ends into the gap in the metal posts and clamp them tightly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grand_pics/grand_6.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Upstage Master Carrier Slack&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the rope is secured to the master carriers, you can start hanging the curtain on the hooks hanging from the carriers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;hanging-the-curtain&quot;&gt;Hanging the Curtain&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dump each side of the curtains on their respective side of the stage, and unroll them enough so that you can hang them on the hooks.
You should bring all the carriers back to the offstage ends. Make sure the labeled side of the curtain is facing upstage, and start
hooking the hooks to the grommets on the curtain. The farthest offstage grommet hooks onto the single carrier that is ‘anchored’ offstage,
and the furthest onstage grommet hooks onto the hooks of the master carrier. There should be exactly as many hooks from the single and master carriers
as there are grommets on the curtain. Once all the hooks are attached to the grommets, you’re good to fly the Grand out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you fly it out, have someone watch the slack by the floor pulley and feed it so that it doesn’t catch on itself. If you’re able to fly the curtain all the way out
without picking up the pulley, you’re in luck you got the rope lengths mostly right on your first try.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Try running the curtain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you can close the curtain and open it somewhat easily then congratulations!
You just built out what has historically been the most frustrating piece of equipment we own.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;troubleshooting&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure the stage right segment of rope is at the proper tension and length&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you’ve left off the fold guides of the single carriers. These are the small holes on the little brackets that are connected by a small chain to the single carriers. In previous (incorrect) configurations of the Grand, the rope used to be threaded through these. This is no longer the case, as they seem to serve only to impede the movement of the curtain.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check to make sure the rope isn’t caught around the floor pulley. If it is you probably have too much slack on the stage left segment. Pull more through the upstage master carrier and reclamp.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;striking-the-grand&quot;&gt;Striking the Grand&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pretty much just take everything apart that you set up.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Unclamp the ropes from the master carriers.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Re-attach the clamping bracket after the rope is off.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Remove and reserve the end stops&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take the rope out of the carriers and pulleys (if the stage is bare, try and keep it off the wood)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Take all the carriers (except the ones anchored offstage) off the tracks
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The best / most fun way is to hold a bin at the end off the track and just push them off the track into the bin&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Replace the End Stops&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure the rope is somewhat neatly in the bin&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;folding-the-curtains&quot;&gt;Folding the curtains&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Folding the curtains is easier to get wrong then you may think, and if you get it wrong you may not be able to fit the curtain in its bin,
which, writing from experience is extremely frustrating at the end of a long strike call. Thankfully it’s also easy to fold properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Begin by laying the curtain out flat (or as flat as it will get with its pleats).
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Pull the bottom corners taught, then the top corners.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure the center seam is relatively straight between the top and bottom of the curtain.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the curtain is laid out, you can fold it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Have one person at one top corner and one person at the bottom corner of the same side. Together you’ll fold the curtain from one edge to the center seam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Run and lift the curtain in a similar manner to how you would fold any other of our soft goods (try to catch air).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure that your fold aligns nicely with the seam, and make sure the fold is about as flat as it can be, not overlapping on itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve checked that, fold the other side similarly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the other side is folded, you’re going to fold from the outside edges to the center again, similar to what you just did.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It should look like this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/grand_pics/grand_7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Twice Folded&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you’ve completed the second fold to the center, you’re going to take one side and fold it over the center line to the seam on the other side.
The best way to do this is to get like four or so people to just pick the whole side up and place it across to the seam.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now take the edge of the other side and fold it to the edge of the side you just folded (so over on itself). Once it’s all folded, roll from the bottom to the top.
The roll will be pretty thick, but it should fit nicely in the bin. Once that’s done, repeat the process for the other curtain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After that, thank the Grand for its service and celebrate being done with it for now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, party.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://49.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_ly2hdgDFoL1r4ghkoo1_500.gif&quot; alt=&quot;spongebob&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Penthouse Lightboard Cheatsheet</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/penthouse-lightboard-cheatsheet.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/penthouse-lightboard-cheatsheet</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;startup&quot;&gt;Startup&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Turn on board via power switch under front lip of board&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Make sure all cables are plugged in first.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Board will take a while to start up&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use the top bank of sliders (they are labeled on the board) to create different lighting looks in the room and shift between them&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;if-you-want-to-bring-up-specific-lights-refer-to-the-magic-sheet-image-further-down-this-page&quot;&gt;If you want to bring up specific lights, refer to the “magic sheet” image further down this page.&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Type in the number corresponding to the lights you want to bring up on the number pad.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then hit [@] and a value from 0-100 and then [Enter] to set their brightness.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hit the [Undo] key several times to turn them off and release control of them.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;to-shut-the-board-down&quot;&gt;To shut the board down&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Move the mouse to the top of the screen so the menu bar appears, click on the File menu and then Click Exit.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Then click the power button in the lower left corner of the screen, to the right of where it says “Run Palette.”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The board will then (slowly) shut down.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;if-the-board-crashes&quot;&gt;If the Board Crashes&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;You can hard power down the board by holding down the power button.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Only do this if you absolutely need to!&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/penthouse_board_magic_sheet.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Penthouse Magic Sheet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Node Configuration Instructions</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/node-configuration.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/node-configuration</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Plug the node into the lighting network and write down the ip address taped to the side of the node&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find a Mac (If you’re using a PC, you’re on your own…)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open System Preferences&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go to the Network Preferences page&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Move the “Auditorium” Wi-Fi network&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Click on Advanced towards the bottom right corner of the window&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Go to the TCP/IP page&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In the drop down menu where it says “Configure IPv4” select “Manually”&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Give the computer an ip address of &lt;code&gt;192.168.0.199&lt;/code&gt; (or any other ip address within the
lighting network but not used by an entity on that network)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Give the computer a Subnet Mask of &lt;code&gt;255.255.255.0&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Click Ok and then click Apply&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Open Firefox (other browsers are less successful at interacting with the strand
interface)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Type in the ip address of the mode where you would enter a web address + /mini/&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;If the ip address is: &lt;code&gt;192.168.0.72&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Type in: &lt;code&gt;192.168.0.72/mini/&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;There are only a few things that you should be changing in this screen, depending
upon what you are configuring the node to do:&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;You can change whether the ports (DMX A and DMX B) output or input DMX by
going to their respective pages within this screen by clicking on them and then
selecting DMX in from the drop-down menu&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;You can change what DMX universe (set of 512 DMX channels—usually we’ll just
be using universes one and two to give the hall a total of 1024 addressable channels of lighting control) each port corresponds to by changing the “Netslot” field value of each port along the bottom of the window.&lt;/p&gt;

        &lt;ul&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;To put a DMX port (A or B) in Universe 1, enter “1” for the “Netslot” For Universe 2, you would enter 513 for the “Netslot”&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ul&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;If you reconfigure the node, make sure to change the label for each DMX port to reflect what it is doing, (i.e. if you configure a port to be DMX in second universe, change the label to DMX IN U2)&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Click Update to update the node with the changes you made. The password is &lt;code&gt;2606&lt;/code&gt;. Go back to the DMX A and DMX B pages to make sure the desired changes held.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;After reconfiguring the node, for the changes to take effect, you frequently have to reboot the node by unplugging it from ethernet and then plugging it back in!&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’re done! To make your computer connect to the regular internet again, go back to the Configure IPv4 drop down menu in system preferences and change it back to “Using DHCP” and apply the changes.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>PH Magic Sheet Summer 2015</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/ph-magic-sheet-summer-2015.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/magic-sheet-summer-2015</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Magic_Sheet_Summer_2015.png&quot; alt=&quot;Magic Sheet&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Lighting General Information</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/lighting-info.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/lighting-info</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;control&quot;&gt;CONTROL&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;House Board is Strand Light Palette Classic
Wireless and wired Strand Shownet Ethernet lighting network N21 Ethernet to DMX nodes available
Remote Focus Unit Available
Houselights and Worklights controlled via Strand Vision Net, auxiliary console, and wall panels around the space, as well as through primary console (HTP)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;power&quot;&gt;POWER&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;400 Amp Three Phase Company Switch available for additional power needs, any use of which must be approved in advance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;dimmerscircuits&quot;&gt;DIMMERS/CIRCUITS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Circuits are 1:1 with corresponding dimmers
* 192 Strand C21 Dimmers (1-169 for stage lighting)
* 48 20Amp Non-Dim Circuits (204-223 available)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dimmed Circuits - Stage Pin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1-52: FOH in Catwalks (52)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;53-88: Stage Level (36)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;89-148: on Electrics (60)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;149-157: Permanently wired to Fixed Pars in Ceiling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;158-160: Extra Circuits on Electric 2 (numbered OL 210-212), 161-169: Extra FOH circuits in Catwalks (9) (numbered OL 213-221)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Non-Dim Relays - Twistlock (L5-20) 210-217: FOH in Catwalks (8)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;204-209: Stage Level (6)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;218-223: on Electrics (6)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Work/House Light Circuits&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;170-172: Booth track lights (dim)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;173, 174: Blue Running Lights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;175, 243: Work/Running Lights Back Stage (dim) 176,184: Projector Booth Track Lights (dim) 177,201: Catwalk Access&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;178: North and West Vestibules (dim)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;179: Stage Vestibule (dim)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;181-182: Constant On (Power to House Accents) 193,183,194: Booth work lights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;195, 196: Stage Works&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;197: Catwalk Works&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;198: Projector Booth work lights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;199: Work Lofts Works&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;200: Work Lofts Works&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;241: FOH Works (1st Catwalk)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;244-249: House Lights (dim)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;250-253: House Accents (Dimming Control)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lighting-positions&quot;&gt;LIGHTING POSITIONS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Front of House&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Catwalk 1&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lighting network, dimmed lighting circuits, non-dim power available Throw distance approximately 37’ to Downstage Center&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Length: 47’, Length of ceiling opening: 44’&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Catwalk 2&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Lighting network, dimmed lighting circuits, non-dim power available Throw distance approximately 46’ to Downstage Center&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Length: 47’, Length of ceiling opening: 44’&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Design does not permit lights to be pointed far upstage from this position&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Catwalk 3&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No lighting circuits&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Design does not permit lights to be pointed at the stage from this position&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Catwalk 4&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;No lighting circuits&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Design does not permit lights to be pointed at the stage from this position&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Flown Lighting Positions&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electric 1 (U5)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lighting network, dimmed lighting circuits, non-dim power available 30’ Trim, Length 41’8”, Throw distance approximately 36’ to DSC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Electric 2 (U7)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lighting network, dimmed lighting circuits, non-dim power available 30’ Trim, Length 41’0”, Throw distance approximately 41’ to DSC&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;followspots&quot;&gt;FOLLOWSPOTS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two Lycian SuperArc 400 Followspots with manual color changers are available, usable from the FOH Followspot booth. The throw is approximately 90 ft to the front of the stage. Use of followspots must be approved in advance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;fog-and-haze-machines&quot;&gt;FOG AND HAZE MACHINES&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usage of any fog/smoke/haze/atmospherics must be approved in advance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;strobeslasers&quot;&gt;STROBES/LASERS&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Usage of strobe lighting or lasers must be approved in advance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;pyrotechnics-naked-flame&quot;&gt;PYROTECHNICS, NAKED FLAME&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No pyrotechnics or flames of any sort are allowed in the space&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Followspot Guide</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/followspot-guide.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/followspot-guide</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Followspot_Guide_1.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Follow Spot Guide One&quot; /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/Followspot_Guide_2.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;Follow Spot Guide Two&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A1 Checklist</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/a1-checklist.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-03T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2016/01/03/a1-checklist</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Phase Of Show&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Task&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Clock On &amp;amp; Start Checklist&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Check in with your shift leader for a production meeting&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Necessary speakers flown in to proper height and tested&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Banners In or Out&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Talk back mic and monitoring headphones set up &amp;amp; working&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Input channels patched, tested, gained, working, labelled&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Signal metering on all channels&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Hanging House mics working &amp;amp; showing signal on Mac Pro&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Recording set up &amp;amp; metering at appropriate level&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Opening&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Wireless batteries checked &amp;amp; wireless transmitters sleeved&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Opening&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Stairs to stage in or out&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Opening&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;No extraneous items left on stage&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Opening&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Pre-show music playing &amp;amp; video live if requested&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Show&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Stage Manager and Lighting are ready for show to start&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Show&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Start archival recording as house goes to half&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Show&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Un-mute mics and level before speaker / talent approaches mic&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Show&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Minimize extraneous mic noise (pops when taking mic out of stand or setting on table)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Show&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Watch / listen to performers for non-verbal / verbal cues&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Show&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Listen and check for proper usage of compressors, gates, FX &amp;amp; EQ&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Show&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Follow program or set list for end of show or intermission&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Show&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Establish whether or not performers are coming out for an encore&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Locate, remove, &amp;amp; store / return any borrowed gear&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Test &amp;amp; troubleshoot any malfunctioning equipment, fix or label accordingly&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;On Microwave, save .taf, normalize, compress, normalize, export to mp3, save again, WeTransfer&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Clip, bag, and store each mic, coil XLRs, check on drum rug&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Remove show specific patches in patch bay&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Relocate any articles left in house to office or #122 (NO overnight storage without advance approval)&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Check backstage for misplaced hall items, restore to their homes&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Return rechargeable batteries to charging stations!&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Headphones, talkback mic, cables, adaptors &amp;amp; manual are under desk / put away&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Sequencer is off; SC48 off and covered&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Mac Mini displays &amp;amp; projection systems are off&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Post&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;Confirm with shift manager that you can leave; Clock off&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Setting Up a Board Feed for a Videographer</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2016/01/02/board-feed-for-videographer.html"/>
   <updated>2016-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2016/01/02/board-feed-for-videographer</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;If a group decides they would like a video recording of their event and has hired someone to do so, they may ask for an audio feed from the board. This videographer will probably be doing post production and wants direct raw mic feeds as opposed to using the distance mic on his camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The method for setting up a feed mirroring the board output would be similar to sending audio to a monitor, except that rather than sending the audio to the patchbay, you will be sending it directly to the video camera.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, run an XLR cord from one of the auxiliary outputs on the back of the board to the videographer. You may have to unplug one of the eight auxiliary outputs; remember to plug them back in after the event.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Make sure the cord stays behind the chairs in the house and is taped down whenever it has to cross an aisle or walkway; if crossing an aisle, tape the XLR at the bottom of the steps where no one is likely to trip on it.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If running a feed to the lower level, use very long cables and daisy chain two or more together;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Run them from the mixer ➝ straight out to the wall ➝ down the wall to the lower level ➝ back in to where the video is positioned.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Never run cable across a walkway and make sure they don’t either.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the connection has been made, you will want to send the videographer a test signal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Select the aux you will be using (i.e. Aux #8), then use the mouse to click on System, then find the test signals sending a 100 Hz, 1000 Hz, 10000 Hz, White Noise, or Pink Noise.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Increase the level of sound until the videographer confirms he/she is receiving signal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have confirmed that the camera is receiving signal, ask the videographer what kind of mix he/she would like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Say the videographer wants the house mix; you would need to send all of the audio at the same level as it is coming out of the mains, so you would select all of the channels that will potentially be going live during the event and send them at unity, postfade, to Aux #8, and then raise Aux #8 to unity as well, or to whatever level the videographer decides is best.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Do not adjust the aux level during the show, as it will make everything suddenly sound louder or softer mid-recording.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;If the videographer asks for only vocal mics or instrument mics, select the correct channels and send them to the correct aux.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;In some cases the videographer may choose to do his/her own post-production sound editing, and may want a specific prefade mix. In this case, ask what they are looking for, and adjust accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Remember that sending a channel prefade means the aux will receive signal when the channel fades out, but not when the channel is muted.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Setting Up monitors</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/12/30/setting-up-monitors.html"/>
   <updated>2015-12-30T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/12/30/setting-up-monitors</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;The basic idea here is that you’re sending a certain mix of sounds back to the musicians so they can hear themselves better or other instruments that might be too quiet or far away for them to hear otherwise. This mix is, more often than not, different from the house mix that the audience hears. You are sending audio from a channel to an auxiliary output on the Venue (a separate output from the mains), which goes to the patchbay, then to a floorbox or AVP, then to a monitor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Grab a monitor&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;First, figure out how many monitors will be needed by talking to the band or band leader.  Most musicians will only need one, but sometimes a drummer or lead singer will ask for two.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bring the monitor to stage and set it downstage of the musician who will be using it. Take a look at the direction the speakers inside are facing and try to point them toward the musician’s face. If you are using a Community M12 stage monitor, the square speaker (behind the grill) should be on the side closest to the musician.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find a SpeakOn cable with enough length to reach between the monitor and the nearest floorbox.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Connect either end of the cable to the floorbox (or AVP) Speakon output that you intend to use (just pick one, they’re all the same) and remember that number for patching.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Attach the other end of the speakon to the monitor itself. If there are two identical ports on the back of the monitor, one of them will be your input (usually the one on the left) and the other can be used to daisy chain a second monitor to this one.  However, if you forget which side is which, it does NOT matter; both ports are completely identical.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;IMPORTANT: when plugging in Speakon cable, make sure you push in the end, then twist it clockwise UNTIL IT LOCKS. These cords carry a lot of power, so it’s important that they are correctly fastened. To unlock, simply pull back the grey portion near the end and turn counterclockwise.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Move to the Patchbay&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You will be working in the Speakon patchbay in the rack furthest to the right. They are labeled properly, so just think about what you are trying to do and re-check your output # if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The aux sends are split in the patchbay, so Aux #1 now has two outputs. Take a CROSSWIRED speakon cable, plug one end into the correct Venue aux output, and plug the other end into the corresponding floorbox/AVP port.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At this point, you can now head back up to the board.  Find an assistant to confirm that each monitor is working. Then adjust the mix for each monitor as necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Up at the Venue&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;You’ll first need to “set up” an aux in order to send signal from the board to the monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To set up an aux, first “select” the channel on the board that is holding your signal. That signal could be the microphone on stage, talkback mic at FOH, or from the channel holding your ipod.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;Better yet, use the signal generator found in the Options/Miscellaneous tab and insert it by first turning the OUTPUT VOLUME to -inf dB. Click the volume control to turn it on, selecting the output that you wish to test (using the Select buttons on the Venue desk), and ONLY THEN turning up the volume on the signal Generator.&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;
        &lt;p&gt;The speakers in the Hall can produce Sound Pressure Levels that can permanently damage someones hearing even at a distance; always ensure that the volume is low before engaging the generator so as to ensure that we don’t deafen each other!&lt;/p&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once you’ve got your signal ready and showing strength, select that channel and look on screen and find the “aux” section of the channel strip (it should be toward the top, just left of center). It will have 16 numbered round knobs. Click on the rotary knob (it will turn green) to turn it on, then adjust the rotary knob to your desired level.  Always start low and work your way up.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Now you’ve just sent the channel signal to the aux send, but you still need to send the aux send signal to the stage monitor itself.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;To do that, look over to the group of faders designated for sends on the board. It’s the group of 8 faders just left of the master fader.  Make sure you have selected the button labeled “Aux 1-8” so that you are in the right fader bank. Then, move the Aux #1 fader up to unity, or another good level.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is a good time to decide whether you want this aux to be pre- or post-fade.  Unless you have a valid reason to select otherwise, choose post-fade. This will give you the control of using the aux fader to boost or cut overall signal to that monitor.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Base your levels and EQ solely on the feedback you get from your assistant on stage or the musician listening to it. From 100’ away, you have no clue what it sounds like. Talk to this person in depth to get a feel for how it sounds and how you could make it sound better.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Seven Bad System Dwarves</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/seven-system-dwarves.html"/>
   <updated>2015-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/seven-system-dwarves</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/seven_system_dwarves.png&quot; alt=&quot;Seven Bad System Dwarves&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Setting Up a DI-Box</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/setting-up-a-di-box.html"/>
   <updated>2015-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/setting-up-a-di-box</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;A DI-Box (Direct Input Box) allows you to connect high-impedance sources to a mixer without adverse effects.
The most common uses are for connecting electric keyboards, guitars, bass guitars and most forms of instrument pickups directly to the mixer without using an amp or microphone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plug the 1⁄4” TS cable from the instrument’s pick up into the DI (using the high-Z input)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Plug an XLR into the output of the DI and run that to a system input (floorbox, AVP, snake, etc).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If an amp is involved, but they still want a direct line as well, you’ll have to split the source.
Usually the musician will have his/her instrument plugged directly into the amp, so you’ll have to break this chain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull the plug from the amp input and insert it into either input of your DI box.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Grab a short instrument cable (1/4 inch TS usually) and plug into the THRU port of the DI and then back into the input of the amp.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Getting Sound From a Mic to the mains</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/mic-to-mains.html"/>
   <updated>2015-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/mic-to-mains</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;setting-up-a-mic&quot;&gt;Setting up a Mic&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find out who or what you are miking and how versatile they need to be during the show. Choose a
stand and mic accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find out where the mic needs to be placed on stage. Setup the stand, attach the clip, and slip the
mic into the clip. Make sure everything within the stand is tight.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the mic is wired and you are using a boom stand,
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Take your XLR cable and first plug the male end into the floorbox or AVP.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Carry the coil to the stand (when possible, follow along with other cables going in that same
direction) and drop the coil under the center of the stand.
￼￼￼￼￼* Run the female end up the stand, wrapping it around once.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;As you hit the boom, make sure the cord runs over the tightening pin.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Wrap the cord once more around the boom in the same direction.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Plug the female end into the mic, making sure the cord has enough slack at the end so that
the mic can be easily adjusted, but not so much that the cord is hanging all over.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Always leave the cable slack at the base of the mic stand, never at the input or somewhere in
between.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Try to run the cables in right angles when possible and along with other cables nearby. However,
avoid running microphone cables alongside AC power cables or SpeakOn unless absolutely
necessary;; this will generate noise in the signal.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Any loose cables onstage or backstage should be taped down after soundcheck is complete, and
prior to doors opening. Remember to not tape down any mics that will need to move around during
the show.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If the mic is wireless, check to make sure the battery has at least two bars for a rehearsal setting
and three for a public performance. Batteries with less than two bars should be recycled in the
“dead battery” bin.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-patchbay&quot;&gt;The Patchbay&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;This is where you will be connecting the signal directly to the SC48. Check the number on the floorbox or AVP input you plug into;; it should be in the format of the letter M then a sequence of ascending numbers, example: M12. Take a long-frame cable and run it from that input to whichever channel you intend to use on the mixing board. Use different colored cables to show different groups of mics (wired vs wireless or vocals vs instruments or input to split to SC48 vs booth).&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;While patching, make sure the sound system is on by checking that the sequencer key is turned to “on” and that all its associated amps have turned on. While you’re doing this, check the subwoofer amp and turn on manually if needed.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;at-the-venue-sc48&quot;&gt;At the Venue SC48&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Turn on the Venue if it hasn’t been turned on yet. Once it is on, make sure all channels have been
muted or have their faders turned down. Then turn the master fader (at the far right) up to “unity”.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Select each channel you have patched mics to and label them by double clicking on the “Channel #”
in the top left corner of the onscreen interface and naming what instrument or type of mic it is (“SL Vox” for stage left vocals, or “W1” for wireless mic #1). This makes it easier to keep track of your mics and keeps you from forgetting which channels are which.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you are using a condenser mic, remember to mute the channel before turning on phantom power because the 48 volts will cause the mike to pop momentarily. If the mic is not muted, the entire house may hear an very loud and unpleasant sound. To engage phantom power:
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Select the channel that needs the phantom.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Again, make sure the channel is MUTED and the fader is down.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Press the 48V button near the top of the Venue.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Unmute, gain and then fader up.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find someone assigned as or willing to temporarily be your audio assistant to test the mics. Have them first go to each mic and test that each one is working by gently tapping the grill of the mic. You are checking to see that you are getting signal to the channel;; if you see nothing, turn up the gain until you do. Remember to keep the channel muted and fader down while line checking.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Once you have completed the line check, you know all your patches are correct, and you have extra time and want to do things right, you can now do your pre-soundcheck soundcheck! Ask your assistant to go back to each mic and spend more time with each one. They should speak through vocal mic and play approved instruments, one at a time, to help you set gains and test monitors.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;During line check, confirm that each channel is going to the appropriate main speaker (LR or C). To do this, decide whether the sound from each independent channel should be coming out of the left and right speakers, the center speaker, or all three. * As a rule, vocalists should be routed to the center speaker only, instruments to the left and right and pre-recorded music again to just left and right (although left, center, and right is also an option if you need more level). On the board, select the channel, then choose the L/R or Center assigns from the master mains routing section.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Adjust the panning, limiter, comps, gate and effects (FX) as you see fit. These should all be adjusted pre-show;; turning any of these on mid-show would have to be done very gradually and strategically. When done improperly, you could lose sound completely and totally throw off a performance.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Double check that the speakers are at the the right height for the show.
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For a lecture or panel, the center speaker can be the only one down.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Instrumental performances can have the left and right speakers down.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For use with the projection screen, left and right should be set below the break in the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For a film screening from the booth, fly the line array below the break in the screen.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At this point the basic loop of mic to patchbay to Venue to speakers is complete. There are a bunch of technical processes in there, but basic mic amplification is taking place, which can be enough for some musical performances and most lecture settings.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Handheld Tascam Tutorial</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/handheld_tascam_tutorial.html"/>
   <updated>2015-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/handheld-tascam-tutorial</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2 id=&quot;initial-set-up&quot;&gt;Initial Set Up&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Press and hold the Home button to turn on the Tascam.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the battery indicator and replace if the battery is low.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check to see if the SD card is actually in the device; if not, find one and insert it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;empty-the-memory-to-ensure-theres-enough-space-for-your-recording&quot;&gt;Empty the memory to ensure there’s enough space for your recording:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Press menu button to get to the menu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use plus or minus buttons to scroll down to others, press enter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scroll down to system, press enter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Scroll down to quick format, press enter.  Exec, enter.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“All data erased. Are you sure?” Press enter and you’re done.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press menu to get back to the record screen and press the Rec Mode button to choose an input.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay in “stereo” and then select your input under “source”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your source will be either “Internal microphone” or “External in 1&amp;amp;2” (your XLR 1&amp;amp;2).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pressing menu again will bring you back to the home screen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;there-are-three-methods-of-taking-a-recording-in-the-penthouse&quot;&gt;There are three methods of taking a recording in the Penthouse:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;strong&gt;Plan to use the Tascam’s built-in mic as default because it is much easier and you can place it anywhere.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To record using the mic, all you need to do is press record twice to begin the recording.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure to test it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the group specifically wants you to take a board feed:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect 2 XLRs between Stereo Alt Out on the back of the board and the Tascam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Press the little AB button near the master fader to enable the output&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the side of the Tascam, choose “Line” under the the Ext In selector&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test the mics and ensure you’re getting signal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If the group specifically asks you to get a recording from the hanging house mics:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Start in the patch bay and connect the “hanging house mics 2 &amp;amp; 3” to the AVP nearest your mix position&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect two gender changers and XLRs from that AVP to the Tascam&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the side of the Tascam, choose “Mic+Phantom” under the Ext In selector.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Test the mics and ensure you’re getting signal&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the performance ends, press the stop button and eject the SD card.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bring the SD card to the computer in the recording booth or at FOH and insert it into the USB SD card reader (or insert it into any cage laptop checked out).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Download the content to the Archival Audio file folder and use the naming convention as follows:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year.Month.Date_Description_Engineer.mp3 (Example: 14.3.19_FOTA_Kyle.mp3)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, send the file to:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;erinbrenner@uchicago.edu
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to the website WeTransfer.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload the recording to the site&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter Erin’s email address (above)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enter your email address press Send.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now go put the SD card back into the handheld Tascam device and you’re done!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Archival Recording Instructions and Standards</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/archival_instructions.html"/>
   <updated>2015-12-29T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/12/29/archival_instructions</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting up the Audio Console:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn the board on (button on the back of the board center)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose “Filing” from the options tab at the top of the display&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select the “Load” tab&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you don’t have your own preset, choose “Performance Hall” folder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select “Archival Recording Preset”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Press the button “Load”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting up the Mac Mini:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Turn on the monitor display to the Mac Mini&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click on your empty desktop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose “Go” in from the options tab at the top of the display&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Select “Applications”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open “Microwave”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Setting up your session:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change the Sample Rate to 44100&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change the bit depth to 24 bit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Change the channels to stereo if showing mono&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click “Create”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Name your session according to the naming protocol below (don’t include the .mp3)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the arrow next to the file name to drop down the filing menu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save the file under “Documents” -&amp;gt; “PH_Recordings”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Testing the recording during rehearsal:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Press the record button to enable recording (large red circle) while making noise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Press the same record button to stop recording&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you see a very slight waveform, it means your recording is working, but you want more signal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gain the hanging house mics until you see a better waveform. Congrats! You’ve got a recording going.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Drag the timing bar back to the beginning of your recording; it will allow you to record over your test&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Record the show:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press Record both before and after the show&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Normalize, Gain, Normalize:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;From the drop down menu at the top of the screen choose “Effects” then “Normalize”; allow it to process&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Next, also under “Effects”, choose “Dynamics Processor” and press “Apply” on the pop up window&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Normalize again by repeating step 1: “Effects” and “Normalize”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Choose “File” -&amp;gt; “Export”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ensure that the Output File Format is MPEG 2 Audio Layer III (.mp3) and press “OK”&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Name the file the same way you named the session (according to the naming convention below)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the arrow next to the file name to drop down the filing menu&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Save the file under “Documents” -&amp;gt; “PH_Recordings”&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Send the file to erinbrenner@uchicago.edu:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open Chrome or Safari (using the same method you used to open Microwave or from the dock below)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go to the website WeTransfer.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Upload the recording -&amp;gt; enter Erin’s email address -&amp;gt; enter your email address -&amp;gt; press Send&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Naming Convention:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Year.Month.Date_Show_Engineer.mp3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:    14.8.31_ThirdCoastPercussion_Remy.mp3&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Example:    15.2.24_MEME_Jace.mp3&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Microphone List</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/12/26/microphone-list.html"/>
   <updated>2015-12-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/12/26/microphone-list</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shure SM 58: Dynamic (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common uses: Live vocals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rugged, sound source should be very close to the grill&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shure Beta 58: Dynamic (Supercardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common uses: Live vocals, Voice-over&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sounds brighter than the SM58&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shure SM 57: Dynamic (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common uses: Guitar &amp;amp; Bass amp, Brass, Percussion&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rugged, very similar to the SM58&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sennheiser MD 421: Dynamic (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common uses: Toms, Bass amp, Guitar&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sennheiser e609: Dynamic (Supercardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common uses: Guitar amp, Brass&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shure KSM 137: Small-Diaphragm Condenser (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common uses: Acoustic Bass &amp;amp; Guitar, Cymbals, Percussion, Strings, Piano, Woodwinds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delicate mic, Requires phantom power
￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio-Technica AT U853R: Small-Diaphragm Condenser (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use: Hanging microphone found in the Penthouse for distance miking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delicate mic, requires phantom power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Audio-Technica AT-4050 Multi-pattern Condenser (Cardioid, Figure of Eight, Omnidirectional)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Use: Solid all around instrument microphone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delicate mic, requires phantom power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shure SM 27: Large-Diaphragm Condenser (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common uses: Acoustic Bass &amp;amp; Guitar, Brass, Strings, Percussion, Piano, Woodwinds&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phantom power required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shure SM 87A: Large-Diaphragm Condenser (Supercardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common uses: Live vocals&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Slightly smoother EQ curve in high end than SM58&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phantom power required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PCC-160: Pressure Zone Microphone (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Common uses: Floor or wall mic for distance miking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phantom power required, will pick up room sounds&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shure ULX2-58: Dynamic Wireless (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SM58 equivalent wireless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;WL185: Condenser Lavalier Wireless (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Basic wireless clip on mic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Phantom power required&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Shure ULX2-87A: Condenser Wireless (Cardioid)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;SM87A equivalent wireless&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;DPA 4090: Condenser (Omnidirectional)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hanging mics found in the Performance Hall for distance miking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Delicate mic, requires phantom power&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;MX418S: Condenser (multiple pattern cartridges included)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lectern Gooseneck Microphone&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Audio Equipment and Set-Up</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/12/26/equipment-and-setup.html"/>
   <updated>2015-12-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/12/26/audio-equipment-and-setup</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;stands--safety&quot;&gt;Stands &amp;amp; Safety&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The hall has two basic types of stands: boom stands and straight stands.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Straight stands:&lt;/strong&gt;
 Given that they are less versatile than boom stands, straight stands are generally used to hold microphones for vocal performance or speaking. We usually use straight stands for wireless mics because they are easier to move around the stage, but they can take any standard mic clip. Our straight stands have a heavy round base and an adjustable neck. The connector at the neck twists right to tighten and left to loosen;; adjust the stand to the appropriate height and tighten the neck.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Boom stands:&lt;/strong&gt;
 Given that they can be contorted into good positions for picking up sounds from many different instruments (including drums, strings, brass, woodwinds, etc), boom stands are more adept for miking instruments. When using a wired mic on a boom stand, the cable should be wrapped a couple of times across the length of the boom, over the pin, and down the length of the stand. Do not wrap the cord too many times;; just enough to keep it from flailing everywhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Safety:&lt;/strong&gt;
 Each time you want to make a change to a stand, loosen one joint, adjust the length/direction, tighten and move on to the next joint until the stand acts how you want it to and will hold the weight of the mic you’re about to put on it. Pay attention to how the legs are aligned when you position the stand. If the stand seems unstable, position it so that one of it’s legs is directly under the boom arm. Make sure every joint is tight before walking away from it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When disassembling, also remember to work with one joint at a time. It is very easy to get your fingers
￼￼￼pinched between the moving parts, so be very careful when adjusting and always tighten! The goal when disassembling, is to minimize the space it takes up, so shorten all lengths and align all arms and legs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;cables&quot;&gt;Cables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Performance Hall uses XLR, TRS, Mini TRS, SpeakOn, Cross-wired SpeakOn, Ethernet and Longframe patchbay cables.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;XLR:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most frequently used cord in the hall for passing audio signal. Three-pin XLR cords are able to pass a balanced signal that travels farther than unbalanced signal. Generally XLR cords run from a wired microphone and into Floorboxes, AV panels off-stage (AVPs), or to a snake.
The hall has 10’, 25’, and 50’ XLR, stored on the bottom shelf of the backstage cabinet. When running cable from a mic to a floorbox input, you should look at the length from the stand to the input and choose a cable length that will give you a few feet of slack, as performers may move the stands during soundcheck and occasionally midshow. Leave the slack at the base of the mic stand and not near the input location or somewhere in between.
If the stands will be in the same place during the whole show, you should tape down all the cables in order to create a safer walking space for the performers and a cleaner look for the audience. When taping on stage use the brown gaff tape;; it will blend into the wood and make the stage look cleaner. Any backstage cable taping should be in black gaff as it is less expensive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1⁄4” TRS Instrument Cable:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also known as 1⁄4” cable, “tip, ring, sleeve” or instrument cable. We don’t stock a variety of lengths in the hall because musicians typically bring their own. We do own a few shorter patch length 1⁄4” cables that could run from an amp, keyboard or an instrument with a pick-up to a DI box. These are kept in the storage closet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mini TRS:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also known as 1⁄8”, 3.5mm or aux cable, are commonly used audio cables for connecting phones, ipods and computers to an audio system. While these devices normally have an 1⁄8” input, you often need to convert it to an XLR or 1⁄4” output when connecting to a mixer. In the hall we have a TRS 1⁄8” to stereo XLR cable connected to the mixer at FOH for device connection, but we keep a spare in the storage closet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SpeakOn:&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Used for running sound to floor wedges/monitors, usually from Floorboxes or AVPs. SpeakOn cables vary in length, so choose the appropriate length for each monitor. Floor Monitors that use a SpeakOn input usually will not require any external power;; all the monitors we have are “passive” and therefore do not require any external AC power adaptor. SpeakOn is stored on the audio shelf next to the backstage cabinet.
Crosswired SpeakOn: ONLY used in the patchbay for connecting Venue outputs to the appropriate floorbox or AVP connections. These cords are about 2.5’ and stay in the amp room at all times;; they are marked CROSS on the neck of the cable.
Long-frame/Military cords [Patchbay cords]: Green, red, and black cable used in the patchbay to connect mic inputs to the Venue or Recording Booth. Also used to split signal when necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coiling-cables&quot;&gt;Coiling Cables&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are two methods for coiling an XLR cable and there is much debate as to which is better. In the hall, we use the “over/under” method. This same method can be used to coil almost all other audio cables.
￼￼￼￼￼￼
￼First, hold the female end of the cable in your left hand with the connector pointed toward you. Pull your right hand out along the cable until you reach about 18” and bring that length up into your left hand while guiding
it into becoming your first loop. Pay attention to the direction your right hand rotates as you guide the cable into making this first loop. You are about move your right hand in the exact opposite direction when making the second loop.
After grabbing this first loop in your left hand, pull another 18” with your right hand. This time you’ll loop it up under itself, by twisting in the opposite direction, and again place it in your left hand. The cable should still be moving in the same direction, away from you, it’ll just be coming in from underneath the current coil.
Continue repeating these two steps “over and under) until you hit the end of your cable. Inspect the cable for a proper coil and then use the velcro tie attached to secure. It should look like a series of same sized loops, no figure 8’s. If yours has a figure 8, you must start over. If you have both large and small loops within one coil, start over. If one of your tails is way longer than the other, fix it by adjusting the position of the velcro.
If you have a hard time getting good coils, use this video to help while practicing: http://www.lifehacker.com.au/2012/04/use-these-alternating-coil-methods-for-knot-free-cables/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;speakers&quot;&gt;Speakers&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main speakers:&lt;/strong&gt; Also known as the “mains”. In the Performance Hall our mains are in a L-C-R (left, center, right) configuration. They are Electro-Voice, or “EV” brand speakers, model: Xi2123A/106, and are flown to heights controllable from the automated rigging system “Scene Control”. The projection system has its own surround sound system with a L-C-R EAW KF740 Line Array.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitors:&lt;/strong&gt; Also known as “wedges” or “floor wedges”. We have 3 different monitor speakers;; 3 of the smaller 12” EV’s (TX 1122 FM), 2 of the 15” EV’s (TX 1152 FM), and 2 of the 12” Community (M12’s). Monitors should be placed in front of a musician who needs to hear himself, or his fellow musicians, more clearly. While the EV’s need to be set further away from the artist because of how the speakers are pointed within the wedge, the Communities have a wider range and can be placed much closer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Subs:&lt;/strong&gt; We own 2 EV X-SUB’s that live in the work lofts to the left and right of downstage. The subs supply the low end frequencies to both the main and projection systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sidefills:&lt;/strong&gt; The 2 side fills we have, EV Zx1’s, are built into the downstage left and right walls, just where the plank design ends. The side fills are also tied to both the main speakers and the projection audio system.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Audio Glossary</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/12/26/audio-glossary.html"/>
   <updated>2015-12-26T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/12/26/Audio-Glossary</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A/D Converter:&lt;/strong&gt; Analog to digital converter, a device that transforms incoming analog signals into digital signals.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;AFL:&lt;/strong&gt; An acronym for After Fade Listen, another way of saying post-fader solo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux Send:&lt;/strong&gt; A mixer bus output designed to send a signal to an auxiliary processor or monitor system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Aux Return:&lt;/strong&gt; A mixer input with limited control capabilities, intended for bringing the output of an auxiliary processor or other line-level source into the main mix bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balanced Input:&lt;/strong&gt; An input consists of two leads, neither of which is common to the circuit ground. This is a “differential pair”, where the signal consists of the difference in voltage between the two leads. Balanced input circuits can offer excellent rejection of common-mode noise induced into the line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Balanced Output:&lt;/strong&gt; In a classic balanced audio circuit, the output is carried on two leads (high/+ and low/-) which are isolated from the circuit ground by exactly the same impedance. A symmetrical balanced output carries the same signal at exactly the same level but of opposite polarity with respect to ground. A special case of a balanced output carries the signal on only one lead, with the other lead being at zero voltage with respect to ground, but at the same impedance as the signal-carrying lead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bandwidth&lt;/strong&gt;: The band of frequencies that pass through a device with a loss of less than 3dB, expressed in Hertz or in musical octaves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cardioid:&lt;/strong&gt; Heart-shaped. In sound work, cardioid refers to the shape of the sensitivity vs. direction plot for a particular style of directional microphone. A cardioid mic rejects sound arriving from the rear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Channel:&lt;/strong&gt; A functional path in an audio circuit: an input channel, an output channel, a recording channel, the left channel and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Channel strip:&lt;/strong&gt; The physical realization of an audio channel on the front panel of a mixer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Clipping:&lt;/strong&gt; A form of severe audio distortion that results from peaks of the audio signal attempting to rise above the capabilities of the amplifier circuit. To avoid clipping, reduce the system gain in or before the gain stage in which the clipping occurs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Compressor:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a dynamic processor used to smooth out any large transient peaks in an audio signal that might otherwise overload your system or cause distortion. The amplitude threshold and other parameters such as attack time, release time, and ratio are adjustable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Condenser:&lt;/strong&gt; Condenser microphones require electrical power to run internal amplifiers and maintain an electrical charge on the capacitor. They are typically powered by internal batteries or “phantom power” supplied by an external source, such as a mixing console.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Cueing:&lt;/strong&gt; In broadcast, stage and post-production work, to “cue up” a sound or video source (a record, a sound effect on a CD, a song on a tape) means to get it ready for playback by making sure you are in the right position on the “cue,” making sure the level and EQ are all set properly. This requires a special monitoring circuit that only the mixing engineer hears. It does not go out on the air or to the main mixing buses. Cueing can also refer to a similar process regarding video playback.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D/A converter:&lt;/strong&gt; Digital-to-analog converter, a device that transforms incoming digital signal into analog form.
￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Decibel (dB):&lt;/strong&gt; A unit used to measure the intensity of a sound or the power level of an electrical signal by comparing it with a given level on a logarithmic scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Delay:&lt;/strong&gt; In sound work, delay usually refers to an electronic circuit or effects unit whose purpose it is to delay the audio signal for some short period of time. Delay can refer to one short repeat, a series of repeats or the complex interactions of delay used in chorusing or reverb. When delayed signals are mixed back with the original sound, a great number of audio effects can be generated, including phasing and flanging, doubling, Haas precedence-effect panning, slap or slapback, echo, regenerative echo, chorusing and hall-like reverberation. Signal time delay is central to many audio effects units.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dry:&lt;/strong&gt; Usually means without reverberation, or without some other applied effect like delay or chorus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dynamic microphone:&lt;/strong&gt; The class of microphones that generate electrical signals by the movement of a coil in a magnetic field. Dynamic microphones are rugged, relatively inexpensive, capable of very good performance and do not require external power.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Equalization (EQ):&lt;/strong&gt; Refers to purposefully changing the frequency response of a circuit, sometimes to correct for previous unequal response (hence the term, equalization), and more often to boost or cut the level at certain frequencies for sound enhancement, to remove extraneous sounds, or to create completely new and different sounds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Frequency:&lt;/strong&gt; The number of times an event repeats itself in a given period of time. The audio frequency range is generally considered to be 20 Hz to 20, 000 Hz. This covers the fundamental pitch and most overtones of musical instruments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gain:&lt;/strong&gt; The measure of how much a circuit amplifies a signal. Gain may be stated as a ratio of input to output voltage, current or power, such as a voltage gain of 4, or a power gain of 1.5, or it can be expressed in decibels, such as a line amplifier with a gain of 10dB.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gate:&lt;/strong&gt; A dynamics processor that automatically turns off an input signal when it drops below a certain level. This can reduce the overall noise level of your mix by turning off inputs when they are not in use. Threshold, attack time, hold, and release time are some of the adjustable gate parameters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Graphic EQ:&lt;/strong&gt; A graphic equalizer uses slide pots for its boost/cut controls, with its operating frequencies evenly spaced through the audio spectrum. In a perfect world, a line drawn through the centers of thecontrol shafts would form a graph of the frequency response curve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ground:&lt;/strong&gt; Also called earth. Ground is defined as the point of zero voltage in a circuit or system, the reference point from which all other voltages are measured.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In electrical power systems, ground connections are used for safety purposes, to keep equipment chassis and controls at zero voltage and to provide a safe path for errant currents. This is called a safety ground. Maintaining a good safety ground is essential to prevent electrical shock.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In sensitive electronic equipment, tiny currents and voltages riding on the ground (so it’s not truly zero volts) can cause noise in the circuits and hamper operation. Often a ground separate from the power ground is used as the reference point for the electronics, isolating the sensitive electronics from the dirty power ground. This is called a technical ground.
Hertz: The unit of frequency, equal to 1 cycle per second. Abbreviated Hz. kHz = 1000 Hz, and is usually pronounced “kay” (with “Hertz” implied) by sound professionals who ask for “a little more two and a half K” when they want you to boost 2.5 kHz (2500Hz).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Impedance:&lt;/strong&gt; A measure of the AC resistance, capacitance, and inductance in an electrical circuit, measured in ohms;; all of these three properties impede the flow of current. AKA: the higher the impedance, the lower the current. In audio circuits (and other AC circuits) the impedance in ohms can often be much different from the circuit resistance as measured by a DC ohmmeter. Maintaining proper circuit impedance relationships is important to avoid distortion and minimize added noise.
Level: Another word for signal voltage, power, strength or volume. Audio signals are sometimes classified according to their level. Commonly used levels are: microphone level (-40 dBu or lower), instrument level (-20 to -10 dBu), and line level (-10 to +30 dBu).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;￼￼￼￼￼&lt;strong&gt;Line level:&lt;/strong&gt;  A signal whose level falls between -10 dBu and +30 dBu.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Main (house) speakers:&lt;/strong&gt; The main loudspeakers for a sound reinforcement system. These are usually the largest and loudest loudspeakers, and are usually positioned so that their sound seems to come from the area of the main stage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Master:&lt;/strong&gt; A control affecting the final output of a bus on which one or more signals are mixed. A mixer may have several master controls, which may be slide faders or rotary controls.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mic level:&lt;/strong&gt; The typical level of a signal from a microphone. A mic level signal (usually but not always coming from a microphone) is generally lower than -30 dBu. With a very quiet source (a pin dropping?) the signal can be -70 dBu or lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mic preamp:&lt;/strong&gt; Short for microphone preamplifier. An amplifier whose job is to bring the very low microphone level signal up to line level, or in the case of a mic preamp built into a mixer, the mixer’s internal operating level (approximately 0 dBu). Mic preamps often have their own volume control, called a trim control, to properly set the gain for a particular source. Setting the mic preamp gain correctly with the trim control is an essential step in establishing good signal-to-noise ratio and sufficient headroom for your mix.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Monitor:&lt;/strong&gt; In sound reinforcement, monitor speakers (or monitor headphones or in-the-ear monitors) are
those speakers used by the performers to hear themselves. In recording, the monitor speakers are those used by the engineer and production staff to listen to the recording as it progresses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Noise:&lt;/strong&gt; Whatever you don’t want to hear. Could be hum, buzz or hiss;; could be crosstalk or digital hash or your neighbor’s stereo;; could be white noise or pink noise or brown noise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Normal:&lt;/strong&gt; A wiring method which electrically ties together two jacks or two poles of one jack so that in normal operation, there is signal flow between them. Inserting a plug breaks this connection, allowing the signal path to be modified. Normal wiring is common in patchbays and insert jacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PA:&lt;/strong&gt; Acronym for Public Address. An electronic amplification system used as a communication system in public areas. Today, people who work with PA systems like to say they’re working in “sound reinforcement”. Pan, pan pot: Short for panoramic potentiometer. A pan pot is used to position (or even dynamically move) a monaural sound source in a stereo mixing field by adjusting the source’s volume between the left and right channels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patch bay:&lt;/strong&gt; A collection of usually a large number of jacks allowing convenient access to various points in a system’s interconnect wiring. A patch bay can make re-routing signals very convenient without having to fish around with cables in the back of racks or consoles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Parametric EQ:&lt;/strong&gt; A “fully” parametric EQ is an extremely powerful equalizer that allows smooth, continuous, and independent control of each of the three primary EQ parameters: frequency, gain, and bandwidth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;PFL:&lt;/strong&gt; An acronym for Pre Fade Listen. Sound folks call it being able to solo a channel with the fader down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phantom Power:&lt;/strong&gt; A system of providing electrical power for condenser microphones (and some electronic pickup devices) from the microphone input jack;; it provides +48V across two pins in a 3-pin XLR. The system is called phantom because the power is carried on standard microphone audio wiring in a way that is “invisible” to ordinary dynamic microphones. Generally, phantom power is safe to use with non-condenser microphones as well, especially dynamic microphones. However, unbalanced microphones, some electronic equipment (such as some wireless microphone receivers) and some ribbon microphones can short out the phantom power and be severely damaged. Be careful!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Phase:&lt;/strong&gt; The time relationship between two signals, expressed in degrees around a circle. 0 and 360 degrees represents an in-phase relationship – both signals change in the same way at the same time. Anything else
is out of phase. 180 degrees out of phase is a special case which, for a continuous waveform, means that at any given time the two signals have the same amplitude but are opposite in polarity. The phase reverse switch found on some mixers or mic preamps actually reverses the signal polarity. When out-of-phase signals are mixed, there will be some cancellation at certain frequencies, the frequencies and the degree of cancellation being a function of the amount of phase shift and the relative amplitude of the signals. Attention to mic placement and careful listening will allow you to use this effect creatively.
￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼￼&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Post-fader:&lt;/strong&gt; A term used to describe an aux send (or other output) that is connected so that it is affected by the setting of the associated channel fader. Sends connected this way are typically (but not always) used for effects.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Pre-fader:&lt;/strong&gt; A term used to describe an aux send (or other output) that is connected so that it is not affected by the setting of the associated channel fader. Sends connected this way are typically (but not always) used for monitors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Return:&lt;/strong&gt; A return is a mixer line input dedicated to the task of returning processed or added sound from reverb, echo and other effects devices. Depending on the internal routing of your mixer and your own inclination, you could use returns as additional line inputs, or you could route your reverb outputs to ordinary line inputs rather than the returns.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Reverb:&lt;/strong&gt; The sound remaining in a room after the source of sound is stopped. Reverberation and echo are terms that are often used interchangeably, but in audio parlance a distinction is usually made: reverberation is considered to be a diffuse, continuously smooth decay of sound, whereas echo is one or more distinct, recognizable repetitions of a word, note, phrase or sound which decreases in amplitude with every repeat. Highly reverberant rooms are called live;; rooms with very little reverberation are called dead. A sound source without added reverb is dry;; one with reverb or echo added is wet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signal-to-noise ratio:&lt;/strong&gt; This is a specification that describes how much noise an audio component has compared to the signal. It is usually expressed in dB below a given output level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Surround sound:&lt;/strong&gt; Multi-channel audio playback systems in 6, 8, or 10-channel formats. Surround sound is typically found in movie theaters and home theater systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TRS:&lt;/strong&gt; Acronym for Tip-Ring-Sleeve, the three parts of a two-conductor (plus shield) phone plug. Since the plug or jack can carry two signals and a common ground, TRS connectors are often referred to as stereo or balanced plugs or jacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;TS:&lt;/strong&gt; Acronym for Tip-Sleeve, the two parts of a single conductor (plus shield) phone plug. TS connectors are sometimes called mono or unbalanced plugs or jacks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Unbalanced:&lt;/strong&gt; An electrical circuit in which the two legs of the circuit do not have the identical impedance to ground. Often one leg is also at ground potential. Unbalanced circuit connections require only two conductors (signal “hot” and ground). Unbalanced audio circuitry is less expensive to build, but under certain circumstances is more susceptible to noise pickup.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Projection Cheat Sheet</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2015/10/03/projection-cheat-sheet.html"/>
   <updated>2015-10-03T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2015/10/03/projection-cheat-sheet</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3 id=&quot;basic&quot;&gt;BASIC&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;SOURCE = MacMini or FOH HDMI&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Turn the Switcher Rack On (Black on / off flip switch, right side)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;On the AMX Touch interface, hit “Turn on system and projector”&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Open Chrome on the Mac Mini and Open the Kumo Bookmark&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Click Projector on the Bottom Row&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Select your source on the Top Row&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/Hs68lLj.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image One&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;if-that-doesnt-get-you-an-image-now-we-start&quot;&gt;If that doesn’t get you an image now we start:&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a name=&quot;troubleshooting&quot;&gt; &lt;em&gt;TROUBLESHOOTING&lt;/em&gt; &lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure you are actually sending some sort of image from your source: (very helpful to have the preview monitor at FOH set to the same source as the projector)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If your source is the mac mini, try dragging a window to the right&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If you’re using a different source, make sure your display preferences are set up correctly&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure the lamp of the projector is actually on
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;In Chrome, open the &lt;strong&gt;Projector&lt;/strong&gt; bookmark. On the top left side there will be a little button that says Lamp and it will have on and off buttons on either side of the label. Make sure “ON” is selected.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure the image is not muted&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/xncCve2.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image Two&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;intermediate&quot;&gt;INTERMEDIATE&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;source--stage&quot;&gt;SOURCE = STAGE&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AFTER YOU HAVE ALREADY DONE THE &lt;strong&gt;BASIC&lt;/strong&gt; INSTRUCTIONS&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get the Decimator, its power adaptor, and one of the long Blue SDI Cables* from Janice [When using the SDI cables, be gentle with them, be careful not to kink them, and please coil them properly when striking] . You may also need an extension cord and / or a power strip.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get whatever adaptors / other cables you need to be able send an HDMI signal to the Decimator from your source. (Probably a Thunderbolt to HDMI, or DVI to HDMI)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect one end of the Blue SDI Cable to the SDI OUTPUT on the Decimator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect the other end of the SDI Cable to one of the AVP Patch Points (If Downstage Right, use AV12, and run the cable up over the doorway.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect your source HDMI cable to the Decimator’s HDMI INPUT&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Confirm that your AVP Patch point (the one to which you connected the Blue SDI cable) is patched to AV38 in the patchbay (The default patching is AV12 to AV38)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;On the KUMO Routing Interface (Chrome), select Projector on the Bottom Row and STAGE on the Top Row.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That &lt;em&gt;should&lt;/em&gt; get you an image. If it doesn’t, refer to the &lt;a href=&quot;#troubleshooting&quot;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/a&gt; section above.
section above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then, if none of that works:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check Your SDI Patching.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check to make sure the Decimator is on (the screen will be lit).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check the BNC Patching in the Patchbay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check to make sure AV38 at FOH is actually connected to something, it should be SDI input #3 on the back of the AJA in the rack.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;refocusing--sizing-the-image-basic-without-presets&quot;&gt;REFOCUSING / SIZING THE IMAGE (Basic/ Without Presets)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure the projector is on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Open the projector interface on chrome&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the “Basic Control” tab on the left&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Use the sets of arrows to adjust the image according to what you need&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;For this you only have coarse adjust:&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;When you click an arrow it will continue to adjust in that direction until you click the square in the center of the arrows&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Also, when focusing, try and have someone on stage close to the screen (or whatever you’re projecting onto) to confirm the focusing&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/5Jrk0p3.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image Three&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;refocusing--sizing-intermediate--with-presets&quot;&gt;REFOCUSING / SIZING (Intermediate / With Presets)&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can do all the same things you can do from the web interface, and more, from the projection booth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go into the projection booth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Check to make sure the computer is on
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;The computer is in the left rack, underneath the HDCam players, and underneath the screen that pulls out&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;It’s a 1U rack unit with a disk drive on the left and a “SuperLogics” logo, there is a red power button on the right.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Push the power button and the fan will start up, letting you know that it’s on.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pull out the screen drawer (the black handle on the rack unit above the computer)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click the &lt;strong&gt;DCCs2&lt;/strong&gt; icon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In the communication settings window, make sure &lt;strong&gt;Projector&lt;/strong&gt; is selected&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The IP Address is:  &lt;code&gt;192.168.1.134&lt;/code&gt; Port is: &lt;code&gt;43728&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/hx6h4VI.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image Four&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Click OK (Also, the projector must be on in order to communicate with it. If it’s not on, nothing further will work. &lt;em&gt;And how were you planning to size an image if it’s off anyways?&lt;/em&gt; :P&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/O1bGrL9.png&quot; alt=&quot;Image Five&quot; /&gt;
7. Once the communication loading bar has completed and gone away, click the &lt;strong&gt;lens&lt;/strong&gt; tab at the top.
8. From the lens tab you have access to the focusing and resizing adjustments, as well as Fine Adjust mode, and &lt;em&gt;presets&lt;/em&gt;
	* SAVING A PRESET&lt;/p&gt;

 		* Make all the image adjustments you need
 		* Click the &lt;strong&gt;Memory List&lt;/strong&gt; button to access the list of presets, then click a new row under all the ones that currently exist
 		* Click &lt;strong&gt;Entry&lt;/strong&gt;, and name your preset, once it’s named you’re all good
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;LOADING A PRESET&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

 		* Select the preset you want to load
 		* Click the &lt;strong&gt;Test&lt;/strong&gt; button, and the preset will begin to load

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;confidence-monitors&quot;&gt;CONFIDENCE MONITORS&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using the Confidence Monitors is sort of the opposite of running a source from the stage in terms of signal flow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Get out the Confidence Monitor rack case from Janice, grab one of the blue SDI cables, and get as many monitors and heavy duty DVI cables as you need.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Set up the case where it will live during the show, it needs power and needs to be relatively close to both an AVP, and the monitors to which you will be running the DVI cables.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect the power cord for the rack supply, and turn the rack on. There should be blue and green lights that indicate that the unit is on.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect the blue SDI cable to one of the AV patch points on the AVP&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Make sure the patching in the patchbay is set up properly so that the AV patch point where you connected the SDI cable is hooked up to the point from where the signal at FOH is sending.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Connect the DVI cables from the back of the inside of the confidence monitor rack to the monitors you will be using, making sure to run the cable out of the way and to be gentle with the cable.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Introducing Lanyon</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2014/01/02/introducing-lanyon/"/>
   <updated>2014-01-02T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2014/01/02/introducing-lanyon</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Lanyon is an unassuming &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; theme that places content first by tucking away navigation in a hidden drawer. It’s based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt;, the Jekyll butler.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;built-on-poole&quot;&gt;Built on Poole&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Poole is the Jekyll Butler, serving as an upstanding and effective foundation for Jekyll themes by &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/mdo&quot;&gt;@mdo&lt;/a&gt;. Poole, and every theme built on it (like Lanyon here) includes the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Complete Jekyll setup included (layouts, config, &lt;a href=&quot;/404&quot;&gt;404&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;/atom.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt;, posts, and &lt;a href=&quot;/about&quot;&gt;example page&lt;/a&gt;)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly design and development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Easily scalable text and component sizing with &lt;code&gt;rem&lt;/code&gt; units in the CSS&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Support for a wide gamut of HTML elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Related posts (time-based, because Jekyll) below each post&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Syntax highlighting, courtesy Pygments (the Python-based code snippet highlighter)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lanyon-features&quot;&gt;Lanyon features&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the features of Poole, Lanyon adds the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Toggleable sliding sidebar (built with only CSS) via &lt;strong&gt;☰&lt;/strong&gt; link in top corner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sidebar includes support for textual modules and a dynamically generated navigation with active link support&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two orientations for content and sidebar, default (left sidebar) and &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/lanyon#reverse-layout&quot;&gt;reverse&lt;/a&gt; (right sidebar), available via &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; classes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/lanyon#themes&quot;&gt;Eight optional color schemes&lt;/a&gt;, available via &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;body&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; classes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/lanyon#readme&quot;&gt;Head to the readme&lt;/a&gt; to learn more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;browser-support&quot;&gt;Browser support&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lanyon is by preference a forward-thinking project. In addition to the latest versions of Chrome, Safari (mobile and desktop), and Firefox, it is only compatible with Internet Explorer 9 and above.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;download&quot;&gt;Download&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lanyon is developed on and hosted with GitHub. Head to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/lanyon&quot;&gt;GitHub repository&lt;/a&gt; for downloads, bug reports, and features requests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thanks!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Example content</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2014/01/01/example-content/"/>
   <updated>2014-01-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2014/01/01/example-content</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;div class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
  Howdy! This is an example blog post that shows several types of HTML content supported in this theme.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis &lt;a href=&quot;#&quot;&gt;dis parturient montes&lt;/a&gt;, nascetur ridiculus mus. &lt;em&gt;Aenean eu leo quam.&lt;/em&gt; Pellentesque ornare sem lacinia quam venenatis vestibulum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Curabitur blandit tempus porttitor. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo. Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Etiam porta &lt;strong&gt;sem malesuada magna&lt;/strong&gt; mollis euismod. Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;inline-html-elements&quot;&gt;Inline HTML elements&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HTML defines a long list of available inline tags, a complete list of which can be found on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTML/Element&quot;&gt;Mozilla Developer Network&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To bold text&lt;/strong&gt;, use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;strong&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;To italicize text&lt;/em&gt;, use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;em&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Abbreviations, like &lt;abbr title=&quot;HyperText Markup Langage&quot;&gt;HTML&lt;/abbr&gt; should use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;abbr&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, with an optional &lt;code&gt;title&lt;/code&gt; attribute for the full phrase.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Citations, like &lt;cite&gt;— Mark otto&lt;/cite&gt;, should use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;cite&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;del&gt;Deleted&lt;/del&gt; text should use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;del&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;ins&gt;inserted&lt;/ins&gt; text should use &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;ins&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Superscript &lt;sup&gt;text&lt;/sup&gt; uses &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;sup&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt; and subscript &lt;sub&gt;text&lt;/sub&gt; uses &lt;code&gt;&amp;lt;sub&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of these elements are styled by browsers with few modifications on our part.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;heading&quot;&gt;Heading&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vivamus sagittis lacus vel augue rutrum faucibus dolor auctor. Duis mollis, est non commodo luctus, nisi erat porttitor ligula, eget lacinia odio sem nec elit. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;code&quot;&gt;Code&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis &lt;code&gt;code element&lt;/code&gt; montes, nascetur ridiculus mus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-js&quot; data-lang=&quot;js&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Example can be run directly in your JavaScript console&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Create a function that takes two arguments and returns the sum of those arguments&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;var&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;adder&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;new&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nb&quot;&gt;Function&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;a&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;b&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&amp;quot;return a + b&amp;quot;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// Call the function&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;adder&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;c1&quot;&gt;// &amp;gt; 8&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur. Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;lists&quot;&gt;Lists&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus. Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur. Etiam porta sem malesuada magna mollis euismod. Fusce dapibus, tellus ac cursus commodo, tortor mauris condimentum nibh, ut fermentum massa justo sit amet risus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Praesent commodo cursus magna, vel scelerisque nisl consectetur et.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Donec id elit non mi porta gravida at eget metus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Donec ullamcorper nulla non metus auctor fringilla. Nulla vitae elit libero, a pharetra augue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Vestibulum id ligula porta felis euismod semper.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Cum sociis natoque penatibus et magnis dis parturient montes, nascetur ridiculus mus.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Maecenas sed diam eget risus varius blandit sit amet non magna.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cras mattis consectetur purus sit amet fermentum. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
  &lt;dt&gt;HyperText Markup Language (HTML)&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;The language used to describe and define the content of a Web page&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;Cascading Style Sheets (CSS)&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;Used to describe the appearance of Web content&lt;/dd&gt;

  &lt;dt&gt;JavaScript (JS)&lt;/dt&gt;
  &lt;dd&gt;The programming language used to build advanced Web sites and applications&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Integer posuere erat a ante venenatis dapibus posuere velit aliquet. Morbi leo risus, porta ac consectetur ac, vestibulum at eros. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;tables&quot;&gt;Tables&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aenean lacinia bibendum nulla sed consectetur. Lorem ipsum dolor sit amet, consectetur adipiscing elit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;thead&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Name&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Upvotes&lt;/th&gt;
      &lt;th&gt;Downvotes&lt;/th&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/thead&gt;
  &lt;tfoot&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Totals&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;21&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;23&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tfoot&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Alice&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;10&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;11&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Bob&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;3&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Charlie&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;7&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nullam id dolor id nibh ultricies vehicula ut id elit. Sed posuere consectetur est at lobortis. Nullam quis risus eget urna mollis ornare vel eu leo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Want to see something else added? &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/poole/issues/new&quot;&gt;Open an issue.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>What's Jekyll?</title>
   <link href="performancehall.github.io/2013/12/31/whats-jekyll/"/>
   <updated>2013-12-31T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>performancehall.github.io/2013/12/31/whats-jekyll</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; is a static site generator, an open-source tool for creating simple yet powerful websites of all shapes and sizes. From &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll/blob/master/README.markdown&quot;&gt;the project’s readme&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Jekyll is a simple, blog aware, static site generator. It takes a template directory […] and spits out a complete, static website suitable for serving with Apache or your favorite web server. This is also the engine behind GitHub Pages, which you can use to host your project’s page or blog right here from GitHub.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s an immensely useful tool and one we encourage you to use here with Lanyon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Find out more by &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/mojombo/jekyll&quot;&gt;visiting the project on GitHub&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
